Those neo-Nazis are going to burn that district!
Kelompok Neo-Nazi akan membakar distrik itu.
That Turkish woman was killed.
Perempuan Turki itu dibunuh.
We're almost at the location designated by Johan.
Kita hampir sampai di lokasi yang ditunjuk Johan.
We don't know what will happen.
Setelah ini, entah apa yang terjadi.
You know how to use your gun, yes?
Kau pandai gunakan pistol, 'kan?
Go to Frankfurt.
Belok ke arah Frankfurt.
Kalvin Street.
Jalan Kalvin.
Are you not on your way to kill Johan?
Kau tak ingin membunuh Johan?
We'll leave that for later. Go now.
Itu nanti saja. Cepat.
General Wolf will be most disappointed.
Jenderal Wolf pasti kecewa berat.
He had high hopes for you when he requested that you eliminate Johan.
Dia berharap banyak saat memintamu membunuh Johan.
Requested?
Meminta?
I answer to no one's requests.
Aku tak sudi menuruti permintaan siapa pun.
I will kill Johan of my own volition.
Aku akan membunuh Johan atas kemauanku sendiri.
Go to Kalvin Street now.
Cepat ke Jalan Kalvin.
Each point has confirmed they are ready to set the fire.
Tiap pos menyatakan siap memulai pembakaran.
Good work.
Kerja bagus.
Adorn the festival of our superior race with your spectacular flames.
Hiasi festival ras unggul kita dengan api kalian.
Yes, sir!
Baik!
Now, then.
Nah.
What do we do with them?
Kita apakan mereka?
Even the superior race has filth like this.
Ras unggul pun punya sampah seperti mereka.
One of them is a petty thief
Satunya pencuri kelas teri,
and the kid tried to tip off the Turkish people about our actions.
dan bocah ini hendak membongkar aksi kita ke warga Turki.
Both are trash.
Keduanya sampah.
Let's purge them.
Ayo binasakan mereka.
I completely agree.
Aku setuju.
This place is also gonna burn anyway.
Toh tempat ini juga akan terbakar.
Come on, don't cry.
Ayolah, jangan menangis.
Your mommy will come back for sure.
Mamamu pasti akan pulang.
Ay--
Ay…
You were alive?
Kau masih hidup?
How'd you find me?
Tahu dari mana alamatku?
Dieter told me your general location.
Dieter memberitahuku acuan lokasinya.
Dieter?
Dieter?
So, the Tenma that he talked about was you after all.
Ternyata benar kau Tenma yang dia maksud.
Where is Dieter? He came here, right?
Dieter di mana? Dia kemari, 'kan?
What? No.
Apa? Tidak.
He hasn't?
Tidak?
More importantly, where's Ayse?
Ayse di mana?
This is Ayse's son.
Ini putra Ayse.
He needs to be held by his mother soon.
Anak ini butuh pelukan ibunya.
It can't be…
Tak mungkin…
I won't accept that.
Aku tak percaya itu.
What about this baby?
Bayi ini bagaimana?
He's so small.
Dia masih sangat kecil.
What will he do without his mother?
Bisa apa tanpa ibunya?
I won't let there be any more victims.
Takkan kubiarkan ada korban lagi.
Let me meet the community leaders.
Pertemukan aku dengan para senior distrik ini.
What do you think?
Apa pendapat kalian?
They'll set the place on fire?
Mereka akan membakar distrik ini?
Those far-right people have been talking about it all year.
Kelompok sayap kanan ekstrem mengungkitnya terus sepanjang tahun.
We can't believe everything they say.
Jangan asal percaya.
Besides, it's suspicious
Orang Jepang ini mencurigakan.
that this Japanese guy came here if it's so dangerous for him.
Kalau memang berbahaya, kenapa dia malah datang kemari?
Hey, Ayse died for this, you know.
Hei, Ayse mati demi informasi ini.
She was killed for trying to warn everyone about this.
Dia dibunuh karena berusaha mengingatkan warga.
I'm not too sure.
Aku tak yakin.
Ayse is a prostitute like you, right?
Ayse itu PSK sepertimu, 'kan?
You people sell yourselves to German guys and disappear.
Kalian pergi setelah menjual diri ke orang Jerman.
It's a common story.
Sering terjadi.
A disgrace to the Turkish people.
Cuma jadi aib bagi orang Turki.
Who does that brat even belong to?
Kita juga tak tahu siapa ayah anak itu.
I'm sure you all know well that they have no choice but to do such things to live.
Kalian pasti paham mereka tak punya pilihan lain.
Listen to me if you want to survive.
Dengarkan aku jika ingin selamat.
Whatever!
Sudahlah!
Do whatever you want!
Terserah kalian saja!
Go and burn, the lot of you!
Semoga kalian terbakar!
Come now, wait just a moment.
Hei, tunggu sebentar.
Is this about forming a vigilante group?
Kau ingin membentuk tim siaga?
Let's try following what the Japanese man says.
Mari kita coba turuti orang Jepang ini.
Deniz!
Deniz!
Will you really listen to this suspicious Japanese guy?
Masa menuruti orang Jepang mencurigakan ini?
He is indeed suspicious.
Dia memang mencurigakan,
But there are some Japanese people we should believe.
tapi ada orang Jepang yang harus kita percaya.
Like General Nogi.
Misalnya, Jenderal Nogi.
General Nogi?
Jenderal Nogi?
You don't know him?
Kalian tak kenal dia?
The one who saved the Turkish Navy when it was stranded in the Pacific
Penyelamat AL Turki yang terdampar di Samudra Pasifik
was a Japanese man named General Nogi.
adalah pria Jepang bernama Jenderal Nogi.
I see.
Begitu.
Gather all the men in the district.
Kerahkan semua pria di distrik ini.
This looks so delicious!
Kelihatannya enak!
I see today is another special dinner.
Ini makan malam spesial, ya?
Slow down.
Tunggu.
You mustn't eat in such a rush.
Jangan makan terburu-buru.
You'll end up finishing your meal before showtime.
Nanti makananmu habis sebelum acara utamanya.
The show should reach its climax right around when the main dish arrives.
Puncak acaranya mesti tepat saat hidangan utama datang.
Just for tonight,
Khusus malam ini,
I'll enjoy my 1976 Château Latour, which I save for special occasions…
akan kunikmati Château Latour 1976 yang kusimpan untuk acara istimewa.
and feast on my favorite raw flounder with caviar.
Juga hidangan favoritku, ikan sebelah mentah dengan kaviar.
And soon enough…
Dan bersamaan dengan itu…
See?
Itu dia.
Look, the first flame has been lit.
Lihat, api pertama sudah dinyalakan.
But that is still only just an appetizer.
Tapi ini baru hidangan pembuka.
When is the main dish?
Kapan hidangan utamanya?
Didn't I tell you not to be in such a rush?
Sudah kuingatkan jangan buru-buru, 'kan?
Enjoy your meal slowly and a great show will…
Nikmati santapannya pelan-pelan, acaranya akan…
Where is the main dish?
Di mana hidangan utamanya?
If that fire is the appetizer,
Jika api itu untuk hidangan pembuka,
which part will you burn for the main?
di mana yang dibakar untuk hidangan utama?
-Over here! -Bring the water!
- Di sini! - Ambil air!
We're out of fire extinguishers!
Pemadam apinya habis!
Don't go all at once. Follow me if you have a free hand.
Jangan sekaligus. Yang bisa bantu, ikut aku.
As I thought, the fire started upwind.
Sudah kuduga, diawali dari arah angin datang.
That means it's dangerous here too.
Berarti di sini bahaya.
Let's split into three.
Ayo bagi jadi tiga tim.
Oh my, what a wonderful guest we have here.
Wah, kita kedatangan tamu istimewa.
-You… -Don't move!
- Sial… - Jangan bergerak!
I'll shoot for real.
Atau kutembak dia.
Put that dangerous thing away.
Letakkan benda berbahaya itu.
How about we enjoy this together?
Bagaimana kalau kita nikmati ini bersama?
Unfortunately, the appetizer will disappear.
Sayangnya, hidangan pembukamu akan lenyap.
Well, it is merely an appetizer.
Itu baru hidangan pembuka.
But isn't it your favorite?
Tapi favoritmu, 'kan?
How unfortunate.
Sayang sekali.
Let's just have a good time.
Ayo kita bersenang-senang saja.
This is a festival to welcome your older brother, Johan.
Ini festival penyambutan kakakmu, Johan.
This isn't what Johan wants.
Bukan ini yang diinginkan Johan.
Oh? And how would you know that?
Oh? Tahu dari mana?
I went to take a look at the place he wrote in his message.
Aku pergi ke tempat yang dia sebutkan di pesannya.
What?
Apa?
This isn't what Johan wanted.
Bukan ini yang diinginkan Johan.
What did you see over there?
Kau melihat apa di sana?
He…
Dia…
He didn't want anything.
Dia tak menginginkan apa pun.
I got it.
Aku paham.
Relax. Let's calm down.
Santai. Tenanglah.
You people killed Ayse.
Kalian membunuh Ayse.
I won't let you commit any more atrocities.
Takkan kubiarkan kekejian ini berlanjut.
Where's the main dish?
Mana hidangan utamanya?
What part of town will you set on fire?
Daerah mana yang akan dibakar?
Dammit!
Sial!
They're setting fire to places the fire trucks can't get into.
Mereka membakar tempat yang sulit dijangkau truk pemadam!
Carry the injured.
Papah yang terluka.
I'll be there right away.
Aku segera ke sana.
Tenma.
Tenma.
Did you find Dieter?
Dieter ketemu?
Someone said they saw a kid at the park that looked like him, but…
Ada yang melihat anak mirip dia di taman.
Dieter…
Dieter…
Is it okay to not chase after that woman?
Tak apakah tak mengejarnya?
Yeah.
Ya.
Let's continue the dinner.
Kita lanjutkan makan malamnya.
How impressive. I'd expect nothing less from Johan's sister.
Tapi hebat juga dia, benar-benar adik Johan.
What?
Apa?
Judging from her eyes earlier,
Dari tatapannya,
she really meant to kill me.
dia sungguh berniat membunuhku.
Thanks to that,
Nyaris saja
I was dangerously close to telling her where the main dish really is.
kuungkap lokasi hidangan utama sebenarnya.
Then we will continue your meal.
Kalau begitu, makan malam akan dilanjutkan.
-No, get me my underwear first. -What?
Tunggu. Ambilkan celana dalam dulu.
What a terrifying young girl.
Gadis yang menakutkan.
Wait, I'll put out the fire now.
Sebentar, akan kupadamkan.
You did great, little boy.
Kau hebat bisa bertahan, Dik.
You're safe now.
Kau selamat.
Miss, I don't know who you are, but thanks.
Nona, aku tak kenal kau, tapi terima kasih.
How did you two get in this mess?
Bagaimana kalian bisa terjebak di sini?
Well…
Itu…
It's that kid's fault.
Gara-gara bocah itu.
Geez, we went through so much crap.
Astaga, tadi gawat sekali.
Alright, I'm making my escape now.
Ya sudah, aku mau kabur.
Those guys won't stop with a small fire like this.
Tak mungkin mereka cuma ingin ada kebakaran kecil.
I've lived in this district since I was a kid, so I know well.
Aku tinggal di distrik ini sejak kecil, jadi aku paham.
I wouldn't set a fire here if I'm trying to burn up the district.
Jika ingin membakar habis distrik, bukan tempat ini yang kubakar.
I'm saying this was a decoy.
Intinya, tempat ini cuma pengalihan.
We managed to put out the three fires in the direction of the wind.
Tiga titik api yang searah angin sudah dipadamkan.
Tenma, you have our thanks.
Terima kasih, Pak Tenma.
Right, guys?
Benar?
Yeah.
Ya.
Thanks to you, we ended it before things got bad.
Berkatmu, api bisa dipadamkan sebelum parah.
Anyway, let's tend to the injured.
Mari kita rawat yang terluka.
There won't be any more victims no matter what.
Takkan kubiarkan ada korban lagi.
What do you mean by "decoy"?
Apa maksudmu pengalihan?
The wind's direction changes.
Arah anginnya berubah.
The wind settles at around this time every night
Anginnya berhenti di jam-jam ini,
and a sudden breeze from the river will come next.
lalu tiba-tiba ada angin dari arah sungai.
The wind has settled.
Anginnya mulai tenang.
Now then,
Nah,
it's finally time for the main dish.
saatnya hidangan utama.
Alright, you'll be okay now.
Sudah, kau akan segera pulih.
Thank you, Doctor.
Terima kasih, Dokter.
Let's have a toast.
Mari kita bersulang.
Don't be silly.
Apa maksudmu?
You're injured. Take it easy.
Kau terluka. Istirahatlah.
Don't be so uptight. Right?
Jangan terlalu serius. Ya, 'kan?
Exactly.
Ya.
It's thanks to Dr. Tenma we avoided a big fire in the district.
Berkat dr. Tenma, kebakaran besar berhasil dicegah.
I bet the far-right guys are getting worked up that the fire didn't blaze up.
Kelompok sayap kanan ekstrem pasti kesal apinya tak membara.
No doubt.
Pasti.
Don't sell us Turkish people short.
Jangan remehkan orang Turki.
Where's the other shelter with the injured?
Di mana lagi selter korban luka?
The mosque by the river.
Masjid di dekat sungai.
Hey, Dr. Tenma.
Hei, dr. Tenma.
Take a break.
Istirahatlah. Minum dulu sebelum pergi.
Treating the injured comes first.
Prioritasku merawat korban.
If the fires until now were decoys,
Jika kebakaran tadi cuma pengalihan,
where are they going to set the fire?
mereka akan membakar di mana?
Leave them be.
Biarkan saja.
Who cares what happens to this district?
Siapa peduli keadaan distrik ini?
I have more important matters to attend to.
Aku punya urusan lebih penting.
Wait!
Tunggu!
Please, tell me.
Tolong beri tahu.
Where would you set the fire?
Kalau kau, akan membakar di mana?
I already told you.
Sudah kubilang, 'kan?
The wind from the river will blow in soon.
Angin dari sungai akan berembus.
If they set fire to the old factory by the river, it's game over,
Jika pabrik tua di dekat sungai dibakar, tamat sudah.
since there should be leftover chemicals there.
Di sana banyak sisa bahan kimia.
It's almost time.
Sebentar lagi.
It's time for the main dish.
Waktunya hidangan utama.
Now, fill up my belly.
Ayo, kenyangkan perutku.
It's all going according to plan.
Semua berjalan lancar.
The festival of the superior race will now begin.
Festival ras unggul akan dimulai.
Little boy, why did you follow me?
Dik, kenapa kau mengikutiku?
I need to extinguish the fire.
Aku harus padamkan apinya.
I promised Tenma.
Aku sudah janji ke Tenma.
Tenma…
Tenma…
This is the warehouse.
Ini gudangnya.
What a relief.
Syukurlah.
Maybe they don't know about this place.
Mungkin mereka tak tahu lokasi ini.
Are these all chemicals?
Semua ini bahan kimia?
If all these chemicals catch fire,
Jika semua bahan kimia ini terbakar,
the district won't stand a chance.
distriknya bisa terbakar habis.
Alright, I'll protect this place.
Baik, aku akan melindungi tempat ini.
I'll never let them set this place on fire.
Takkan kubiarkan tempat ini dibakar.
-Ouch… -Are you okay?
- Aduh… - Kau tak apa?
I slipped.
Aku terpeleset.
What is this?
Apa ini?
It's gasoline.
Ini bensin.
There's someone here.
Ada orang di sini.
It's okay. I can walk on my own.
Tak apa. Aku bisa jalan sendiri.
Let's head to the shelter and take a look for now.
Mari kita ke selter dan cek kondisimu.
Sorry about that.
Maaf, ya.
I twisted my ankle when I was carrying out my valuables.
Kakiku terkilir saat mengangkut barang berhargaku.
Now that I have this rug, I have no business in this district.
Permadani ini sudah di tanganku. Selesai sudah urusanku di distrik ini.
A fine rug like this will go for 800,000… no, a million marks!
Permadani seindah ini bisa dijual 800.000, atau sejuta mark!
-Heckel! -Whoa!
Heckel!
Oh, boy.
Sial.
Where's Dieter?
Dieter di mana?
Well, um…
Itu…
I'm asking where Dieter went!
Dieter ke mana?
Oh, that kid went to the old factory by the river.
Anak itu tadi ke pabrik tua di dekat sungai.
The factory?
Pabrik?
Wind from the river will blow in soon.
Angin dari sungai akan berembus.
If the chemicals in the warehouse catch fire, this town is done for.
Jika bahan kimia di gudang pabrik terbakar, habislah distrik ini.
See? This is the wind.
Terasa, 'kan, anginnya?
Tell everyone at the shelter to get away from the river.
Suruh semua orang di selter menjauh dari sungai.
-Hurry! -What?
Cepat!
-Let's go, Heckel. -Huh?
Ayo, Heckel.
Who are you?
Kau siapa?
Who's there?
Siapa itu?
Don't move!
Jangan bergerak!
So, you're Johan's little sister?
Kau adik Johan, ya?
Throw the lighter away.
Lempar korek apinya.
When I set the gasoline on fire,
Saat kubakar bensinnya,
this warehouse will instantly be a sea of flames.
gudang ini akan jadi lautan api.
I'll shoot you in the head before you do.
Akan kutembak kepalamu lebih dulu.
If I sever your cranial nerves, your movements will stop.
Jika saraf otakmu putus, gerakanmu akan terhenti.
Will you hit your mark?
Apa tembakanmu jitu?
I've trained for half a year.
Sudah setengah tahun aku berlatih.
There's no way I'll miss at this distance.
Dari jarak ini, pasti kena.
Threats don't work on me.
Aku tak mempan diancam.
This is a festival for the superior race.
Ini festival untuk ras unggul.
It's for welcoming Johan.
Untuk menyambut Johan.
That's not what Johan wants.
Bukan ini yang Johan inginkan.
It's true that Johan came here, to Frankfurt.
Memang benar Johan ke Frankfurt,
But he left after killing one of your leaders and his men,
tapi dia pergi setelah membunuh pemimpinmu dan bawahannya,
leaving a certain message.
lalu meninggalkan pesan.
A message?
Pesan?
He's not the person you all think he is.
Dia tak seperti dugaan kalian.
He's something far more complex.
Dia jauh lebih rumit.
What are you trying to say?
Apa maksudmu?
He's something far more terrifying.
Dia jauh lebih mengerikan.
He's in the depths of depression, writhing in agony.
Dia sedang tersiksa di dalam jurang keterpurukan.
Oh, geez.
Aduh.
You're making these guys your enemy? Not my problem.
Aku tak ikut-ikutan kalau mereka memusuhimu.
Where's the warehouse?
Gudangnya di mana?
Hey, haven't you done enough?
Hei, apa belum cukup?
I'll take my leave now.
Aku mau pergi.
What are you saying?
Apa maksudmu?
Are you going to let Dieter die?
Kau akan biarkan Dieter mati?
Where's the warehouse?
Di mana gudangnya?
Fine, I'll tell you.
Ya sudah, akan kuberi tahu.
You called your friend "Tenma" earlier, right?
Kau bilang temanmu bernama Tenma, 'kan?
What?
Apa?
I also know someone by the name of Tenma.
Aku juga punya kenalan bernama Tenma.
Really?
Sungguh?
Is he brave too?
Apa dia juga pemberani?
Yes.
Ya,
But I didn't want him to shoot anyone.
tapi aku tak ingin dia menembak siapa pun.
He's not someone who should kill a person.
Dia tak seharusnya membunuh orang.
You must never kill anyone either.
Kau juga tak boleh membunuh orang.
No matter how bad they are?
Termasuk orang jahat?
That's right. Don't copy what I do.
Ya. Jangan tiru perbuatanku.
Close your eyes!
Tutup matamu!
Don't look!
Jangan lihat.
Don't shoot!
Jangan tembak!
Tenma!
Tenma!
Put out the fire!
Heckel, padamkan!
The rug! Hurry!
Permadaninya! Cepat!
Stop, you idiot!
Jangan, Bodoh!
My one million marks…
Permadani sejuta mark…
Nina…
Nina.
Tenma…
Tenma.
Damn, it's the cops.
Sial, ada polisi.
Run!
Lari!
Leave that man to me.
Biar kutangani pria itu.
There's a boat at the river.
Ada perahu di sungai.
Hurry up and run, Tenma!
Cepat kabur, Tenma!
My main dish is cold now.
Hidangan utamaku jadi dingin.
POLICE
POLISI
Thank you for your cooperation.
Terima kasih atas kerja samanya.
Let's talk details at the station.
Mari bahas di kantor polisi.
Wait, I'll be right back.
Sebentar, aku segera kembali.
What? Hey, you!
Apa? Hei!
Tenma!
Tenma!
Nina!
Nina!
Nina, promise you won't shoot!
Nina, berjanjilah, jangan menembak!
You mustn't shoot anyone!
Kau tak boleh menembak!
I saw Johan's message!
Aku melihat pesan Johan!
I saw it too.
Aku juga melihatnya.
I'm heading there now.
Aku akan ke sana.
I finally understand what he meant ten years ago when I shot at him,
Aku paham maksud ucapannya saat aku menembaknya 10 tahun lalu.
when he told me to aim for his head!
Saat dia menyuruhku menembak kepalanya!
Johan isn't alone.
Johan tak sendirian.
There are two Johans!
Ada dua Johan!
So, Dr. Tenma,
Jadi, dr. Tenma,
it's not your fault.
ini bukan salahmu.
Once more, I'll…
Sekali lagi, aku akan…
aim for Johan's head.
menembak kepala Johan.
Hey, don't take a detour here.
Hei, jangan mampir ke sini, dong.
Let's just go home already.
Ayo pulang saja.
Geez, I give up.
Astaga, aku menyerah.
I'm starving.
Aku lapar.
I have no money.
Bokek juga.
If only that rug were still okay.
Andai permadaninya masih bagus.
Dammit.
Sial.
This is…
Ini…
"Save me!"
"Tolong aku!
"The monster inside me is about to burst out!"
Monster di dalam diriku akan keluar!"
There are two individuals within Johan.
Ada dua kepribadian dalam diri Johan.